Hello everyone, I'm Sakura Kawasaki from Nakasaka46!
Today I'm here at the Makuhari headquarters of a company that I'm going to collaborate with.
I'm here at the company's headquarters in Makuhari.
That company is Weather News!
Yay!
I'm going to try my hand at being a weathercaster!
Wow!
I was so surprised when I first heard about it that I couldn't believe it was real.
Today, I'll be practicing for the live broadcast, so I'm going to go right away!
I'm off!
I've seen this scenery before.
It's sunny and rainy here in Tokyo.
Thank you for watching.
Here we are.
Ms. Rinon
It's nice to meet you.
I'm Rinon Oshima, weather news anchor.
Pleased to meet you.
I am Sakura Kawasaki, from Nogizaka46.
It's nice to meet you.
I've attended a few of their live concerts.
I have been a fan of Nogizaka for many years.
Today is the first time in three years that Nogizaka will be holding the Jingu concert.
It's going to be 3 days from today!
There were quite a few people there.
I was so envious.
I was so happy to see you sharing your love for Nogizaka in the news theme.
It made me very happy, too.
Please be a good friend to me today.
I look forward to working with you.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
Let's start today.
Since you've come all this way, I'd like to introduce you to a company called Weather News.
I'd like to introduce you to Weather News.
We have booths on both sides.
First of all
From this side.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
I would like to introduce to you...
As you can see here.
It's called Open Weather.
It's a service for ships.
The direction of the wind is this way and the direction of the waves is that way.
The arrows indicate the direction of the waves.
So, based on that, should I take this one?
"You can save fuel by taking this direction.
It's not just electrical forecasting.
Yes, that's right.
With this kind of wind direction.
It's supposed to lead to the ship.
That's right.
A company called WeatherNews
WeatherNews was originally started as a service for ships.
The founder, Mr. Ishibashi, used to work for a trading company.
At that time, he was in charge of a ship
was sunk by a very strong low-pressure called "Bomb Low".
sank due to a very strong low-pressure called a bomb low-pressure.
As a result of such a maritime accident
Ishibashi went on to work in the weather industry
and founded a company called Weather News.
That's amazing.
I'd never heard of it before.
I learned about it when I joined the company.
The other one was luck. This one is a land-based service.
We do more services for rail and road than it says here.
We also provide meteorological services for disaster prevention and transportation.
I'm really surprised.
I've been watching the news for a while now.
The weather forecast is for everyday things.
But today, it's a little bit more than that.
I was surprised to learn about weather that is a step above everyday life.
The scale of it is huge, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
We provide information services to companies on land, sea, and air.
I'm the one who's... I was in, um.
When I was in high school.
A girl named Monet.
A girl who is artificial passed the weather forecaster exam.
And she's trying to prevent disasters by forecasting the weather.
I thought it was really cool.
I used to admire her.
So I admire everyone.
I also saw Welcome Home Monet.
Weather News supported the production of Welcome Back Monet.
Weather News supported the production of Welcome Home Monet.
They supported the production from a weather perspective.
That's why I auditioned.
That's right.
Studying to be a weather forecaster is a lot of work, isn't it?
It's very hard, isn't it?
There are many moments when I lose heart.
But when I'm in the field like this.
I often feel like I don't want to give up.
I'd love to have you as a study friend.
Next, I'd like to go to the floor where the forecast is being made.
I'd like to go to the floor.
It's finally here.
Please, come in.
Thank you very much.
Please join us.
Wow.
I've seen this on TV before.
It's a totally different atmosphere than before.
It's different when it's fast.
I see.
I've seen it on TV.
I'm sure you've seen it before.
That's the studio over there.
This is the forecast.
It's amazing. That's amazing.
There are four of them on this one desk.
How are they separated?
You can't handle them all.
No matter how many eyes you have.
So much information to take into account.
One forecast.
Sunny, cloudy or rainy.
It's a difficult thing to do, isn't it?
I'm glad to hear that.
I'm glad to know the other side of the story.
I can see a lot of the other side of the story.
You get to see a lot of the other side, don't you?
Yes.
Yes, sir.
WeatherNews also offers a personalized service.
We have an app called Weather News.
This app has been downloaded more than 42 million times, and many people are using it.
That's an impressive number.
42 million!
I can't even imagine.
I can't even imagine how many times the size of the Tokyo Dome is.
That's Nogizaka for you.
The way they counted it.
And the secret of its popularity is its high forecasting accuracy.
It's been certified as the most accurate app for the year 2022!
It's right!
We get a lot of sky photos and videos from our users, and the weather report is a big feature of this app.
We get an average of 20,000 a day, from all over the country, and sometimes from overseas.
We also receive many photos of the sky, of course, but we also receive photos of peacocks walking around.
Are there flowers here now? Poppies?
Poppies. It's difficult to find the right kind of flower.
Maybe it's over. It's over, it's over, it's over.
Actually, Castor was sitting there...
Sakura-chan will be sitting there one day.
You can sit there if you like.
Emergency PitchingEmergency Pitching
Rapid
Sorry for interrupting earlier.
Please, by all means, sit here.
I'd like you to meet our guest.
Please, meet our guest.
Pleased to meet you.
Caster, stay here.
We have a forecaster here at the forecast center.
We have a forecaster here at the forecast center, which is very reassuring.
When I came to the studio, I also thought...
I'm surrounded by screens all the time.
Yes, that's right.
There are many monitors in the office.
I can see everything on the screen.
I can check the scenes I'm in.
But there's also information that's not on the screen.
I can read the information that's not on the screen.
It's like a lot of information is already coming in.
I'm going to check it and think about how to convey it to the audience.
I'm going to be working on that throughout the three hours.
Three hours
Three hours.
Live broadcast.
I'm getting nervous.
Do you think you'll be okay?
I was so nervous at first.
But Ms. Rinano was so friendly to me.
I'm really...
It's like this mysterious space.
It's a totally different atmosphere from Nogizaka.
It's an environment where I can focus on what I have to do in a good way.
I thought it was really nice.
I'm glad.
So you're starting to look forward to it, then.
Let's practice a lot for the upcoming live broadcast.
Let's practice a lot! Let's do a lot!
Please do.
This is Nogizaka.
Do you ever use it for other recordings?
Do you ever use the green back?
What do you think, standing there, in this picture of Sakura-chan?
It looks so white.
It's a green background.
I think you can see the cloth here.
Now, if we put the picture together, it will look like this
This is the weather icon.
This is a weather icon.
I've seen it before.
I've been looking at it for a long time.
That's right.
Sakura, you're looking at the monitor right now.
Actually, the camera is disabled.
The camera is the one with the circle in the middle.
So you have to tell the weather while looking there.
That's an instructive technique, isn't it?
It's a very instructive technique, isn't it?
First of all, it's not so much the weather.
Let's get used to the movement.
I'll say, "Here.
Sakura, point to it.
First of all, Hokkaido.
See you later.
Ha-ha-ha.
Sagura-chan looked like that.
If you bend your elbow a little more...
Yes, yes, yes... we'll be together.
Hokkaido, right?
Next, let's go a little farther.
Fukuoka.
In that case...
You hide it like this? Hide them like this?
That's right. Keep walking.
That's how it starts, isn't it?
And the left and right are getting a little confusing, too.
If you want Fukuoka, bend over a little.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Okay.
Then go back and come back to the same position.
That's right.
It moves around a lot.
I didn't really notice it before, but now that I'm here...
But now that I'm here, how do I get back?
Oh, and how to get back?
That's what I was told a lot during the training.
That you still have your hands.
So I was told to just go back along the body like this.
And then...
And then come back in the same position, same posture.
Oh, that's great. You're learning fast. It's like karuta.
Tokyo is the only place with rain today, so may I ask you to tell them it's raining?
It's sunny and rainy here in Tokyo.
Kushiro is stabbing.
We get a lot of reports here at WeatherNews, and we get a chance to showcase them on our show.
Today is a practice session, so we'd like you to actually introduce the reports.
We have a report from Shiraishi in Ishikawa prefecture.
We have a reporter name Ms. Hana Sakamoto from Shiroishi, Ishikawa Prefecture.
If you read the comments here, you will actually be able to comment on the report.
Comment from Ms. Hana Sakamoto, Shiroishi, Ishikawa
We received this from Ms. Hana Sakamoto, Shiraishi, Ishikawa Prefecture.
Yes, I got it from her.
This is a Shiba Inu.
He's a Shiba Inu wearing a yellow outfit.
Oh, hey...
He's trying to look at me, but he won't.
It's a Shiba Inu that won't make eye contact.
It's all right.
It's hard. It's hard.
It's difficult, isn't it?
Good morning to you for receiving
It's a flower
It's a flower, isn't it?
It's a cold morning, drizzling with kappa constitution
I got a comment saying that...
I thought it was drizzling.
I wonder if it was drizzling.
I wonder if it's cold.
Shall we try again?
Hardly.
Courtesy of Hana Shiraishi Sakamoto, Ishikawa
Good morning, I'm Hana. Kappa-tai reporting for duty.
I received a comment that it's a cold morning with drizzling rain
Yes, it's drizzling and the dog is trying to go on, but it's starting to rain, so he wants to go home.
The dog was frozen and probably wanted to go home because of the drizzle.
I understand that, so I don't mean to speak for your feelings, but I think it's also very important to help them.
Thank you very much.
There are a lot of things on the table.
I'm going to talk about this for one minute, three minutes, five minutes.
We had a training session where we had the participants speak for one minute, three minutes, five minutes, and so on.
This was done before her debut.
Sakura-chan, I'd like you to challenge yourself now for your debut as a newscaster.
I would like you to challenge yourself now.
This is the last one.
I'd like to challenge you here.
Yes, I will.
Yes, ma'am.
This is the weather forecast that you're all familiar with.
I'm not sure what it's called, but...
I don't know what it's called, but there's a stick here.
When I was a little girl, I used to watch the weather forecast every day on TV.
I used to watch the weather forecast every day when I was a little girl, and I used to see the weatherman here.
This is where the weathercaster's personality comes out.
It's different for each person.
Some have a pink one here.
Some have a pretty pink one here.Some of them have cute little things on them.
I saw her pointing out the weather like this.
I thought it was really cool
I used to think she was so cool every day in front of the TV.
I've always admired weathercasters so much.
I was so excited to be able to learn the other side of the weathercaster
I was so excited to come here today
I was so excited to come here today.
It's been a wonderful minute and ten seconds.
I didn't know how to explain it.
I think it's a weather stick.
I've been using it in the show for a while now.
But I could tell that Sakura-chan had seen it and admired it.
I think it was great!
You're very kind.
Thank you very much.
So, how was your one-day experience today?
Since I became an idol, I wanted to experience things for the first time in my life.
I wanted to do a lot of things that I have never done before in my life since I became an idol.
But after coming here today, I realized that there are so many things I haven't done yet.
There are so many things that I have not done yet.
I think it's really cool that you can do so much as an adult.
I want to do my best to be like you.
I'm so happy that you could say that about me.
And it was the same when I was around Sakura-chan's age.
And even when I was younger than Sakura-chan, I was waving my penlight and cheering for her.
I was even younger than Sakura-chan when I was waving a penlight and cheering her on so hard.
I'm really honored.
I feel like this is something that really happens in life.
Thank you very much.
I was really nervous.
But your personality is like the sun, and you really light up the way for us.
I'll be waiting for you.
I'll be waiting for you!
Sakura-chan will actually be at the Weather News Live Coffee Time!
Sakura will actually appear on the Weather News Live Coffee Time on May 18 at 11:30 a.m.!
I will do my best based on today's practice!I will do my best based on today's practice.
Let's do our best!
Thank you for watching!